# Luke Johnson

+1 (417)-459-9341 lej212@outlook.com

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a software engineer who works with companies to build robust, maintainable web applications so they can quickly provide value for their customers. I specialize in React, GraphQL, and Node.js (using TypeScript) and have 3+ years of development experience. I help companies bring their ideas to life through the development of applications from building efficient databases to designing elegant user interfaces.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Springfield, MO

January 2019 - Present

Digital Monitoring Products, Inc.

- Develop full-stack web applications from designing databases, building REST and GraphQL APIs, all the way to building the front-end applications using React.
- Design and manage fully-fledged features from design and development through testing and delivery.
- Advocate for user experience improvement for our apps which have 100,000+ users.
- Build GraphQL application using Apollo Server to standardize a diverse set of REST APIs.
- Monitor and update application dependencies so that our tooling and apps are built using the best tools and technologies available.
- Technologies: React, GraphQL, Node.js, TypeScript

WEB DEVELOPER

Springfield, MO

Missouri State Office of Web Strategy and Development

March 2018 - January 2019

- Full-stack, waterfall environment.
- Update websites and web applications. Fix bugs, patch security vulnerabilities, developed new features, and update legacy web pages to modern standards.
- Technologies: JavaScript, ¡Query, Classic ASP, Microsoft SQL Server

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Springfield, MO

O'Reilly Auto Parts, Inc.

September 2017 – January 2018

- Full-stack, waterfall environment. Develop application to centralize documents and manage progress of product development.
- Technologies: Java, Spring Framework, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Elasticsearch

IT INTERN

Carthage, MO

Leggett and Platt, Inc.

June 2017 – August 2017

- Update SQL-based reports and database schemas to handle company divestitures.
- Technologies: Microsoft SQL Server and Microsoft SQL Server Reporting Studio

## **EDUCATION**

#### MISSOURI STATE UNIVERSITY

Springfield, MO

Major: Computer Science

Class of May 2020

Minor: Math

• GPA: 3.7/4.0